# Yaksh Soni

#### Information Technology Engineer

Seeking a Beginner role to enhance and explore my technical knowledge gained in IT field in last three years, to be Dependable Engineer trained to work in stressful situations with workaholic mindset. Satisfying to liverage analytical skills to help company with upcoming challenges.

yakshsoni10@gmail.com 🔀

9737136362

anand, India 👂

linkedin.com/in/yakshsoni in

#### **EDUCATION**

# **B.Tech IT**BVM Engineering College

07/2018 - Present V.V.Nagar,India

#### **HSC**

#### Gujarat Higher Secondary Education Board

06/2016 - 05/2018 Anand,India

Completed with overall
 97.29 percentile.

#### **PROJECTS**

Desktop AI Voice assistant (01/2021 - 05/2021)

- The project was to develop a Desktop Assistant that will be used to identify answers related to user submitted questions.
- Developed on Python 3.7.
- https://yakshsoni.github.io/Desktop-AI-Voice-Assistant/.

Student Attendance App (03/2021 - 05/2021)

 Created in Android Studio with java language and SQLite for data storage. It has the flexible UI for taking students attendance very easily and conveniently.

Social Media Network Analysis (08/2020 - 11/2020)

- For analysis of Social media networks like facebook and instagram
   For Ex which person has more friends or followers.
- Developed on R studio using **R language** for analysis.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **Telemedia**Gurgaon(Airtel)

06/2021 - 07/2021 Anand,India

To help Datamodel creators

- Tools like different api managers swagger, wso2, kong are introduced. Nosql database Aerospike is also introduced.
- Responsible for creating excel sheets that are to be used in creating datamodel.
- To learn about Telemedia, by attending expert meetings.

Contact: Chinmaya Shukla sir - 9599226357

# **Mobile Application Development**The Sparks Foundation

03/2021 - 04/2021 Anand,India

Graduate Rotational Internship Program

To create Application for basic bank transaction

- First task was to improve the professional profile.
- Responsible for creating the bank transaction application which is capable of transacting money from one account to other and show the history for the same.
- SQLite database for storing purpose.

### **SKILLS**

ASP.Net

MySql

HTML

C++

C(Programming Language)

CSS • • • • •

### **CERTIFICATES**

Writing Professional Emails (08/2019 - 09/2019)

Coursera

JAVA Programming (02/2019 - 04/2019)

NICE Computer Education

C++ programming (10/2018 - 12/2018)

NICE Computer Education

C programing (07/2019 - 09/2019)

NPTEL

# **LANGUAGES**

English Hindi

Professional Working Proficiency Pro

Professional Working Proficiency

Guiarati

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

# **HOBBIES**

Outdoor Games Laptop and Mobile Games

Travelling Bhajans Music